Rentt's heading back into
the labyrinth today...
No, he's not supposed to go until
the kidnapping thing calms down.
It wouldn't kill him to take the day off...
Nah, I suppose that's impossible for him.
Not bad.
I've made some adjustments just for you.
Since I know your habits.
He definitely knows who I am...
A New Weapon
and Power
I've given it the ability to use mana,
spirit energy, and divinity, just like you asked.
Try it out.
Okay.
First, magic.
Wow... you're a lot stronger now.
Your mana seems way more powerful.
All I can do is try and force
it into the sword, though.
But I do have some degree of
control over my spirit energy.
And lastly, divinity.
This is a good sword.
Infusing it with divinity
didn't harm it at all.
Look... it's sprouted new leaves.
An effect of the divinity?
It's the only thing I can think of...
Hey, how are you able to use divinity?
That's normally given to
you by the gods, right?
I once repaired a shrine
that had been abandoned.
You're more of a believer than I thought.
I just felt like doing it
for some reason, is all.
I don't even know what god it was.
It must've been a lower-ranking
one, I'm sure.
Hey, can I keep this?
If these sprouts grow, they
might have divinity in them.
Fine with me.
Thanks.
Can I practice a little more?
Sure. What are you going to do, though?
You've tried everything, haven't you?
I want to try them all at once.
Will this do?
Yeah.
Have you ever heard of Mana-Spirit Fusion?
I've heard rumors.
It's a technique that allows you
to massively power up your magic
and spirit skills by using
them both at the same time.
You'd have to be a real master to do that.
Of course.
You screw it up, and your
body explodes, I've heard.
Want to back out?
No, I'll try it.
An explosion wouldn't be enough
to kill this body, anyway.
Here.
Use this.
If this breaks in the process, it's no loss.
You're sure?
Yeah. It can't handle divinity, but
it's a lot cheaper than a new sword.
Perfect for testing.
Okay. First, I put my mana into my sword
and spirit energy into my hand...
I-Is that...
This is tough...
It's like I'm trying to jam something
into a box that's already full.
This is bad... I can't keep it up...
Hey... are you going to add
divinity to what you just did?
That's really dangerous!
I am.
I need power...
If I'm going to be a
Mythril-class adventurer!
Y-You okay?
That looks like trouble!
Hey, the sword can't take any more of that!
The sword turned into a ball?
I'm sorry... your sword...
It's fine.
Divinity has the power to remove impurity
and restore matter to its original state.
So you can't use it with a normal weapon,
'cause it'll break the bonds
holding the it together.
This sword's made to handle divinity,
but it can't take what you just did.
The most you could do is Mana-Spirit Fusion.
Hey... what do I do if I find an
enemy I can't defeat with that?
You want me to make you a dozen that
you just carry around with you?
I don't have the money.
I know that.
I'm gonna need good equipment if
I'm going to become a Mythril.
I need to make a lot of money.
Please!
It's not happening!
But...
I can't take a job that
doesn't come from the guild!
It'll cause a huge
mess for me later.
Please! I'm begging you!
You need to learn when to shut up.
Or do I need to teach you?
Hey.
Wh-Who are you? You look weird...
Let me talk to him.
I think I can take him for all he's worth.
Do what you want with him.
Bye, kid.
He says he'll talk to you.
Um...
Hey.
Who are you?
An adventurer.
I can't promise I'll take the job,
but I can at least hear you out.
Really?
Yeah.
Please defeat the Lord...
the Lord of the Lake!
The "Lord of the Lake"?
What a mess this is...
The reward, and the quest itself,
are both full of problems.
My name is Ryuntus. I'm from Tottsu village.
Right. The one that's several
days to the east, correct?
You know it?
I've heard they have a strange festival.
Yes.
There's a legend that they once offered
up a young, beautiful girl whose body
was brimming with mana to the Lord of the
Lake, in exchange for saving the village.
They still hold a festival once
a year to remember that day.
But this time the Lord of the
Lake actually appeared,
and ate the girl who was playing
the role of the sacrifice!
And...
It's started demanding more sacrifices.
Several of the village
girls have already died...
I see.
Help us!
The next sacrifice is my little sister!
Please!
Ryuntus's wish is to save his
sister, not to kill a monster.
There's no need to fight
the Lord of the Lake.
But...
Something feels really wrong about this.
It's a quiet village.
Yes. It's a small village, but
it used to be much more lively.
But since the Lord of the Lake appeared,
everybody's just gotten so tired...
This way, Rentt.
Right.
What's this mark?
It's a sign.
The house with this mark has to be the next to
offer their daughter up to the Lord of the Lake.
Did the Lord of the Lake put it there?
No, it lives deep in the
lake. No one's ever seen it.
It was probably put here
by a Kelpie that serves it.
A Kelpie? That's a powerful monster.
It is?
Brother?
Amiris! I'm back!
This is Rentt, the adventurer!
He's a Bronze-class!
He's going to save you!
Jeez!
Brother, I told you so many times not to
talk to any weirdos when you went to the city!
But Rentt's a good guy!
You only think that because
he's tricking you!
He looks like a weirdo to me!
That's really mean...
I can hear every word since my senses
got better when I became a monster...
You're Rentt, the adventurer, right?
Yes.
Thank you for listening
to my foolish brother.
No, it's fine.
But the festival of Tottsu village
is an ancient tradition.
I can't selfishly ask to be
the one girl excused from it.
Amiris!
Please, forget what he asked you, and leave.
I was hired by Ryuntus.
Only Ryuntus has the right
to rescind the request.
I'm not rescinding it! Ever!
If you're going to be staying in
this village, please use our home.
But please don't interfere
with the festival.
I'm glad to become the sacrifice.
I'm sorry my sister's so stubborn.
The festival's tomorrow night?
Yes.
From the look of it, Amiris is not
going to run if we tell her to.
What will you do?
I know it's very dangerous.
But if there's any chance my sister
can be saved... I'll do anything!
So please!
Hey, mister, what are you selling?
This is dried meat.
And this?
Dried fruits. Here, try some.
Really?
It looks so good!
But I do have a request...
What is it?
Tell your parents to buy something.
I can't sell anything
because nobody's coming!
Okay!
I'll tell them!
Great. Eat up.
Thank you!
I'm sorry... I want to ask you something.
A monster!
A mons-
He'll eat us!
I've never seen you in this village before.
Here for the festival?
Something like that.
You came at a bad time, then.
The Lord of the Lake is angry right now.
And so the villagers have better things
to do than buy my wares, I guess!
I see.
Rentt!
Lunch is ready!
Okay!
Sorry to interrupt your business.
It's fine.
You should give up on the
festival and head back to town.
All right.
Did you get to take a look at the lake?
Yeah.
Anyway... does that merchant come often?
Yes. They stop here often.
It's quite nice of them.
I see.
Forgive us, Amiris.
No, don't apologize.
The Lord was the one who chose me.
I was sure Ryuntus would
take you and run away...
He was telling everybody we
should call off the festival...
He was?!
If we make the Lord angry, it could
easily destroy this village!
He was so desperate... he was worried about
you, but also the future of this village.
He really is such a fool...
Amiris, can we talk?
No! Don't come in!
The sacrifice must not
meet others so casually!
All right. Then I'll say it here.
I'll take care of things.
There's always a way.
But...
I'm serious.
So you must struggle, too.
Struggle? How?
No human could defeat the Lord of the Lake!
Ryuntus and I will handle
the Lord of the Lake.
That's impossible!
Amiris, don't do anything
to make your brother sad.
He's all the family you have, isn't he?
So struggle.
As long as there's hope...
That's all I wanted to say.
Thank you.
Our Lord, who protects us from
the bottom of the lake...
Each time the horns of your servants
leave their mark, we make our sacrifice.
One sacrifice of treasure,
one, of our daughters.
When the azure light guides,
protect us from disaster...
I'm sorry, Amiris.
We must do this to protect the villlage.
I know, sir.
Do your duty well.
Let's go.
Right.
Amiris, are you ready?
Yes. Let's go.
Rentt! The fog!
Yeah. It appeared at just the right time.
I can't see a thing...
Let's turn back!
The orb...
Looks like our "Lord" has
made his appearance.
Rentt, there's something there!
This is the Lord of the Lake?
Lord, please, calm your anger!
Protect the village! Protect the village!
Stop, Amiris.
You're wasting your time.
I'll sacrifice myself... I'll
sacrifice myself, so...
The orb!
It's just a beacon, nothing more.
Hang on to the ship!
He's floating on the water?!
It's nice to have a friend
who's an alchemist.
Now, then... let's show this
"Lord" for what he really is.
Krakens are normally found in the ocean.
They don't spit fire, either.
What?
It's that weirdo from this afternoon!
Just like I thought.
A mage cast an illusion on the fog,
and then fired Fortia Bolivus.
If you'd just left, you wouldn't
have lost your precious life.
To think the Lord of the Lake was
just an ugly traveling merchant.
I've already lost my life once, anyway.
What the hell are you talking about?
Rentt!
I'm fine. It's over.
What's that ship?
What is happening?
Amiris? Is that true?
Yes.
They pretended to be the Lord,
and demanded sacrifices!
How awful...
Rentt, did you realize from the start?
I did think it was suspicious.
A monster that's been worshipped as the Lord
of an area doesn't just go out of control.
Hey! Where are the other girls?
Answer them!
They're alive!
We were going to sell them for
a fortune in another land!
They're all alive, right?
There's a small hut on the
other side of the lake.
That's where they are!
Get a carriage ready!
We need to go save them!
Right!
Ryuntus, this means the
job is complete, correct?
Yes, of course!
We're doing the festival
over. Stay and watch it.
He's right. You don't
have to leave so soon.
Sorry. Someone's waiting for me in Maalt.
Too bad, then.
Rentt, I won't forget how you
saved the village, and Amiris.
Thank you.
You're welcome. Be well.
Yes, take care!
Rentt!
Amiris, what did you...
I just wanted to thank him, is all!
Thank me, huh?
Then I shall gladly accept your thanks.
Those kidnappers said they didn't
grab anyone but women...
They seem to have nothing to do with
the kidnappings of new adventurers
that Sheila talked about...
I see. So Ryuntus's sister was saved, then?
Yes.
And the other girls are all safe, too.
Excellent.
It's thanks to the magic item you lent me.
It's nice to be able to
walk on water, isn't it?
Yeah.
If it was real, I would've loved
to see the Lord of the Lake.
You were right not to go.
You had a rush job, right?
By the way, Rentt.
You stole the heart of another
girl you saved, didn't you?
Of course not.
I did get a thank you, though.
A thank you, huh?
I'm sure she'll...
She'll forget me before much
time has passed at all.
That's how it is when you're an adventurer.
The gods should punish
you a little, I think.
Dragonblood Flower